lensa.com 2019-06-14

# Privacy policy

## 1\. INTRODUCTION

1.1 Lensa Inc (“we” or “us”) is committed to protecting the privacy of all visitors to this website (“Site”). This policy sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us when you use our online and/or mobile services, the Site, and software provided on or in connection with the Site, and the Site’s related sites and applications (collectively our “Services”). Please read the following privacy policy (“Policy”) carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.

1.2 By using this Site you consent to the collection, use and transfer of the information (including personally identifiable information) that you provide to us in accordance with the terms of this Policy.

We reserve the right to change the contents of this Policy at any time, by posting such changes to this Policy on the Site at least 30 days prior to the change taking effect. It is your responsibility to familiarize yourself with the Policy regularly to ensure that you are aware of any changes. Your continued use of this Site following the posting of any such changes will constitute your acceptance of the revised Policy.

## 2\. INFORMATION COLLECTION

When you visit and register with our Site you will be asked to provide certain information (which may include personally identifiable information) about yourself, including first and last name, company name (optional), address, phone number, and e-mail address, your jobseeker profile, your resume, experience, education and related information and photo. Please note that your photo may be seen by users of the Site and the companies in which you have submitted your application. If you correspond with us by email, we may retain the content of your email messages, your email address and our responses. We may also retain any messages you send through our Services. You may provide us information in user content you post to our Services. (Collectively: “Personal Information”).

Personal Information which you provide to us or we gather from the Site is controlled by: Lensa Inc (17 West Gay Street Suite 50, West Chester, PA 19380; Company registration number: 5554602 (Delaware)).

2.3 We collect Personal Information generally in the following situations:

Information you provide: when you register on the Site or otherwise contact us to obtain information relating to us or our Services, communicate with us by phone, e-mail or otherwise, complete a questionnaire or job application.

2.3.2 Information collected automatically using “cookies” or other electronic means: whenever you interact with the Site, we receive and store certain types of information using “cookies”. We describe how we use “cookies” in clause 5. When you download and use our Services, we automatically collect information on the type of device you use, operating system version, and the device identifier (or “UDID”).

We may collect your location based information for the purpose of refining job recommendations as a part of our Products and Service. We will not share this information with any third party.

Log file information is automatically reported by your browser each time you access a web page. When you use our Services, our servers automatically record certain log file information. These server logs may include information such as your web request, Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, browser type, referring / exit pages and URLs, number of clicks, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed, and other such information.

When you use our Services, we or our third party analytics providers may employ clear gifs (also known as web beacons) which are used to track the online usage patterns of our users anonymously and help us better manage content on our site by informing us of what content is effective. No Personal Information from your account is collected using these clear gifs. In addition, we may also use clear gifs in HTML-based emails sent to our users to track which emails are opened by recipients. The information is used to enable more accurate reporting, improve the effectiveness of our marketing, and make our Services better for our users.

Our Site may contain links to other websites whose information practices may be different to ours. You should consult the privacy notices of those third party sites as we have no control over information that is submitted to, or collected by them.

We use third party analytics, CRM and marketing automation services to help understand use of our Services. These third party analytics services collect the information sent by your browser as part of a web page request, including cookies and your IP address. Their use of this information is governed by their Privacy Policy.

## 3\. USE OF THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT

3.1 We will use your Personal Information for the purpose of providing our Services including for example to create your account, allow you to view, respond to, and save job postings, allow employers or prospective employers to respond to your job posting responses, allow you to post and share your resume on our Services, provide you with job recommendations based upon your history or preferences, and to respond to your enquiries and communicate with you about orders, products, services and promotional offers, to carry out our obligations arising from any agreements entered into between you and us, to notify you about changes to our Services, for our own research purposes, in order to better understand our customers and their preferences and to improve the Services that we offer, to operate the Site and manage your registration.

3.2 We may collect information under the direction of our employer clients and in some cases, may have no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data such employers process. If you are a customer of an employer and would no longer like to be contacted by the employer, please directly contact the employer with which you interacted. If you are a jobseeker under our Services, you should contact us and the employer. With the exception of a jobseeker using the Services, we have no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data we process. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data should direct his or her query to the employer (the data controller). We will retain personal data we process on behalf of employers for as long as needed to provide services to an employer. We will retain this personal information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. If you no longer want to be contacted by an employer, please contact the employer directly.  
3.3 We may use your Personal Information to provide other information, messages, such as newsletters, changes to features of our Services, or special offers, which we think you may find of interest and may allow carefully selected third parties to contact you occasionally about products or services which may be of interest to you. We and any such third parties may contact you by post, telephone or fax, as well as by email. Where relevant, you are given the opportunity to opt-out of receiving this information at the appropriate section of the website when you register your details.

3.4 If you no longer wish to be contacted in the future by us, please send an email to support@lensa.com and insert “unsubscribe” or “stop” as the appropriate subject heading.

3.5 We may use certain information about you and/or your user content internally for purposes such as analyzing how our Services are used, diagnosing service or technical problems, maintaining security, and personalizing content.

3.6 We reserve the right, but have no obligation, to monitor the user content you post on our Services. We reserve the right to remove any such information or material for any reason or no reason, including without limitation if we determine, in our sole discretion, that such information or material violates, or may violate, any applicable law or our Website and Service Terms of Use Agreement, Employer Agreement or Jobseeker Agreement or any amendments thereto, or to protect or defend our rights or property or those of any third party. We also reserve the right to remove information upon the request of any third party.

3.7 We use cookies, clear gifs, and log file information to: (a) remember information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit the site; (b) provide custom, personalized content and information; (c) monitor the effectiveness of our Services; (d) monitor aggregate metrics such as total number of visitors, traffic, and demographic patterns; (e) diagnose or fix technology problems reported by our users or engineers that are associated with certain IP addresses; (f) help you efficiently access your information after you sign in; and (h) track user content and users to the extent necessary to comply as a service provider with the Digital Millennium Copyright Act and other applicable laws; and (i) automatically update the Services related application on your devices.

3.8 We may also pass Personal Information onto third parties in accordance with this Policy.

3.9 If you are an employer any Personal Information or content that you voluntarily disclose for posting to our Services, becomes available to the public. Otherwise only user content (e.g. comments posted on blogs or community forums) will be available to the public. If you remove information that you posted to our Services, copies may remain viewable in cached and archived pages of our Services, or if other users have copied or saved that information. If you respond to a job posting on our Services, we will share your response with the employer that posted the job. We will share Personal Information you upload to our Services during the recruitment process with your prospective employer.

3.10 We will not disclose your Personal Information to any other party or for any other reason, other than as set out in this Policy, without your prior consent, unless such disclosure is permitted or required by law.

3.11 Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our Site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

3.12 UNFORTUNATELY, THE TRANSMISSION OF INFORMATION VIA THE INTERNET IS NOT COMPLETELY SECURE. ALTHOUGH WE WILL DO OUR BEST TO PROTECT YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION, WE CANNOT GUARANTEE THE SECURITY OF YOUR DATA TRANSMITTED TO OUR SITE; ANY TRANSMISSION IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. ONCE WE HAVE RECEIVED YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION, HOWEVER, WE WILL TAKE APPROPRIATE TECHNICAL AND ORGANIZATIONAL MEASURES AGAINST UNAUTHORIZED OR UNLAWFUL PROCESSING OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION AND AGAINST ACCIDENTAL LOSS OR DESTRUCTION OF, OR DAMAGE TO, YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION.

## 4\. Third Parties

4.1 We may share your Personal Information with our other offices or authorized distributors where appropriate and with other entities as described in this Policy. You expressly acknowledge and agree that as part of the Services we provide and you request from us, we will transfer your Personal Information to employers, prospective employers, other recruiters, or other third parties in accordance with this Policy. We cannot ensure that these third parties with whom we share your Personal Information follow practices at least as protective as those described in this Policy, accordingly, we will not be liable to you (whether under the law of contract, the law of torts or otherwise) for any direct, indirect, special or consequential loss; or for any business losses, loss of revenue, income, profits or anticipated savings, loss of contracts or business relationships, loss of reputation or goodwill, or loss or corruption of information or data which may arise from any action or decision taken by the employers or prospective employers as a result of using this Site.

4.2 We may use your Personal Information to provide other information which we think you may find of interest and may allow third parties to contact you occasionally about product or services which may be of interest to you. We and any such third parties may contact you by post, telephone or fax, as well as by email. Where relevant, you are given the opportunity to opt-out of receiving this information at the appropriate section of the Site when you register your details.

4.3 Notwithstanding any other provision, we may also engage a third party service provider for the purpose of identifying users and delivering to them interest-based content and advertisements. We may share Personal Information about you with our partners and may do so non-human readable form to ensure the security of your information. Our partners also may collect information directly from your device, such as your IP address, device ID, information about your browser or operating system; may combine our Personal Information and non-personal information about you with information from other sources; and may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser. To opt-out of third party cookies, please go to http://www.aboutads.info/choices. To opt-out of the use of your mobile device ID for targeted advertising, please see http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices.

4.4 We may also collect forward any and of your Personal Information, as well as hashed or anonymized user data onto third parties, including third party service providers who we engage to help us to provide services to you, including, but not limited to, employers or recruiters, credit card processing and other billing service providers, customer service providers and email service providers, and online advertising service providers. We may also authorize third party service providers to collect information on our behalf, including as necessary to operate certain features of our Site or to facilitate the delivery of online advertising tailored to your interests. We may store Personal Information in locations outside the direct control of ours (for instance, on servers or databases co-located with hosting providers). We will require that such hosting providers to use industry standard methods to safeguard such Personal Information, but we cannot be responsible for any breaches or unauthorized disclosures by such hosting providers.

4.5 Tracking technologies may be used by third parties including but not limited to help determine which ads to show, even if these ads are not on Lensa.com. This includes without limitation setting cookies on users’ browsers and collect user data using cookies or other technologies for such third parties’ own use and subject to their own privacy policies; as well as the collection of hashed user data using cookies/similar technologies from emails/communications. User data and other information collected with these technologies may be combined with information from other sources and data collected across the internet or from other sites.

4.6 In some cases our software and Site are utilized by our partners in a business alliance via their web community. In these cases, the information collected on our Site is available to both companies.

4.7 If we sell, assign or transfer the assets of our business, or if our business is merged, or enters into a joint venture with another business entity, we reserve the right to sell or transfer the databases maintained by us in connection with its business (including any Personal Information provided by you).

4.8 We may disclose Personal Information in response to a legal process, for example, in response to a court order. We also may disclose such information in response to a law enforcement agency’s request or where we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, non-compliance with of our terms and conditions, or as

4.9 We may organize games, offers, contests, or other events or activities on our Site together with a third party partner. If you provide Personal Information to such third parties, you give them permission to use it for the purpose of that event and any other use that you approve. We cannot control third parties' use of your information. If you do not want your information to be collected by or shared with a third party, you can choose not to participate in these events.

4.10 Except as otherwise discussed in this Policy, this Policy only addresses the use and disclosure of Personal Information we collect from you. Our Site may contain links to other websites whose information practices may be different to ours. Other websites accessible through our Site have their own privacy policies and data collection, use and disclosure practices. You should familiarize yourself with the privacy notices of those third party sites as we have no control over information that is submitted to, or collected by them. We are not responsible for the policies or practices of third parties. Additionally, other companies which place advertising on our Site may collect information about you when you view or click on their advertising through the use of cookies. We cannot control this collection of information. You should contact these advertisers directly if you have any questions about their use of the information that they collect.

4.11 Any Personal Information, which you voluntarily display or distribute on the Site and on the Internet can be collected and used by others. This may result in your receiving unsolicited messages from third parties for which Lensa.com is not responsible and has no ability to affect. If you click on a third party job posting and provide that party with your personal information, we have no responsibility or control over that information.

## 5\. COOKIES

5.1 Similar to other commercial websites, our Site utilizes a standard technology called “cookies” and web server log files to collect information about how our Site is used. Information gathered through cookies and Web server logs allow us to monitor Site traffic and to personalize the content of the Site for you.

5.2 A cookie is a very small text document, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier. When you visit a website, that site’s computer asks your computer for permission to store this file in a part of your hard drive specifically designated for cookies. Each website can send its own cookie to your browser if your browser’s preferences allow it, but (to protect your privacy) your browser only permits a website to access the cookies it has already sent to you, not the cookies sent to you by other sites.

5.3 Browsers are usually set to accept cookies. However, if you would prefer not to receive cookies, you may alter the configuration of your browser to refuse cookies. If you choose to have your browser refuse cookies, it is possible that some areas of our Site will not function as effectively when viewed by the users.

5.4 A browser is the software that is used to access the Internet. The most common browser software titles on the market are: Microsoft Internet Explorer, Google’s Chrome, Mozilla Firefox, Apple Computer’s Safari, and Opera. There are a number of ways to manage cookies. You can clear cookies, prevent cookies, delete cookies and enable cookies at your will and for different circumstances. If you use different computers in different locations you will need to ensure that each browser is adjusted to suit your cookie preferences. To find out how to adjust your browser settings to manage cookies please visit:

http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies

5.5 A cookie cannot retrieve any other data from your hard drive or pass on computer viruses.

## 6\. IP ADDRESSES

IP addresses are used by your computer every time you are connected to the Internet. Your IP address is a number that is used by computers on the network to identify your computer. IP addresses are automatically collected by our web server as part of demographic and profile data known as traffic data so that data (such as the web pages you request) can be sent to you.

## 7\. DATA RETENTION

We will retain the Personal Information provided by you for as long as is reasonably necessary for the purposes listed in this Policy.

## 8\. ACCESSING AND UPDATING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

8.1 You may, of course, decline to submit Personal Information through our Services, in which case we may not be able to provide certain services to you. You may update, delete inaccuracies, or correct your account information and email preferences at any time by logging in to your account. You can review, delete inaccuracies and correct the information about you that we keep on file by logging in to your account.

8.2 California law permits California residents to request and receive certain information about disclosure of certain categories of Personal Information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes or choose to opt out of such disclosure. If you are a California resident and a user of the Site and wish to request this information or opt out at any time, please email us at support@lensa.com.

8.3 We will retain your Personal Information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you our Services or retention is required by law or any order of courts or authorities, or for any other similar compliance purposes. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your Personal Information to provide you services contact us at support@lensa.com. We will retain and use your Personal Information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

8.4 To request removal of your Personal Information from our blog, community forums, or testimonials, contact us at support@lensa.com. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your Personal Information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

## 9\. Children

This site is not intended for children under 13 years of age and we absolutely do not collect information about children. This Site does not and will not contact children under age 13 about special offers or for marketing purposes without a parent's permission. No one under age 13 is allowed to provide any Personal Information to Lensa or on the Site.

## 10\. CONTACT

All comments, queries and other requests relating to our use of your Personal Information should be addressed the customer services team at support@lensa.com or by post to 17 West Gay Street Suite 50, West Chester, PA 19380.
